Guide to the Ervin S. Hubbard glass plate negative collection, 1895-1901 MS2381
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ervin S. Hubbard glass plate negative collection
1895-1901
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ridout, Mollie
MS2381
9 Linear Feet
This collection includes glass plate negatives that range in date from 1893-1901, though much of the material is undated. These images' subjects primarily cover geographic locations—including New England, the greater Washington, D.C. area, and New Brunswick, Canada—and portraits.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Geographic Locations and Portraits.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mollie Rideout, 2018(2018.013).
Biographical / Historical
This collection was photographed by Ervin S. Hubbard (1850-1921). As an architect, he worked in St. John, New Brunswick, Canada; Washington, D.C.; Cleveland, Ohio; and back to Washington where he lived until his death. While in Washington, he worked within the Office of the Supervising Architect for the United States Treasury and later the Office of the Quartermaster General of the United States Army. Photography was a passion of his, and his photographs primarily document his home and street scenes in Washington, trips to New England and New Brunswick, and family members.
Mr. Hubbard was born in Holden, Massachusetts on the Hubbard's family farm. Throughout his childhood Mr. Hubbard grew up in Massachusetts between Westboro, Boston, and the farm before entering the Massachusetts Institute of Technology's (MIT) two-year special course in architecture at age twenty-two. He was a detail-oriented person who drew accomplished, precise drawings.
In either 1877 or 1878 while employed by a prominent Boston architect after attending MIT, Mr. Hubbard traveled to the city of St. John, New Brunswick after a fire destroyed a large area of the city. The building activity in St. John was very active after the fire, and Mr. Hubbard was responsible for taking charge of an office in which the architect was interested. In May 1885, he secured a position within the Office of the Supervising Architect for the United States Treasury. A change in leadership occurred three years later, prompting him to retire and secure a new position in Cleveland, Ohio. In 1891, he moved back to Washington to join the Office of the Quartermaster General of the United States Army, where he worked for at least nineteen years thereafter.
While working in St. John, Mr. Hubbard met Sarah E. Prescott, whom he later married. They had two children, Helen and Laurence. Soon after moving to Washington, Mr. Hubbard took up photography as an extension of his artistic pursuits, and he photographed elements of his other hobbies, including gardening, raising pigeons, and traveling. He raised exotic plants at the Hubbard home on 704 20th Street in Washington's Northwest quadrant. He was particularly proud of his prized exotic Amorphophallus plant that he grew in the backyard every summer. The plant's rank stalk reached over six feet tall. Additionally, he raised homing pigeons in an elaborate pigeon house in the backyard. Raising pigeons was a very popular hobby where he grew up in Massachusetts. Lastly, his desire to see the world took him on adventures to Florida, New England, Alaska, Canada, Europe, and Cuba.
In 1906, Helen married J. Edwin Lawton. Subsequently, the Hubbards and Lawtons lived as a three generation family within the Hubbard home at 704 20th Street. The Lawton family was in the wagon and carriage business, but quickly adapted as automobiles became a viable means of transportation. They sold and customized automobiles for prominent clientele including Senators, Congressmen, and other prominent Washingtonians. The Hubbards and Lawtons embraced automobile travel. Mr. Hubbard's earliest recorded automobile adventure recorded was a ten day camping trip from Washington to Maine and then New Brunswick to visit Mrs. Hubbard's Prescott relatives. The family traveled in a 1916 Buick seven passenger touring car, which Mr. Lawton outfitted with a custom trailer fitted to have a tent set up over the wagon bed. Mr. Hubbard photographed their camps throughout the journey. Afterwards, the family traveled to New England or Canada almost yearly. He kept detailed diaries of these trips, including sights seen along the way.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes glass plate negatives that range in date from 1893-1901, though much of the material is undated. Ervin S. Hubbard, an architect, photographed these images. These images' subjects primarily cover geographic locations—including New England, the greater Washington, D.C. area, and New Brunswick, Canada—and portraits.
Photography; Negatives (photographic); Ridout, Mollie
- Geographic locations, 1893-1901; Series 1
  Arrangement
  This series is organized into four subseries: New Brunswick, Canada; Illinos, New England, and New York; Maryland, Virginia, and Washington D.C.; and Unidentified Locations
  Scope and Contents
  Geographic Location This series contains glass plate negatives of various geographic locations photographed by Hubbard. The subjects of these images predominantly feature known locations including Maine, Massachusetts, Maryland, Virginia,Washington, D.C., and New Brunswick, Canada, but many glass plate negatives are of unidentified locations. The material in this series is dated from 1893-1901, though much of the material remains undated. As a whole, this series focuses on topographical images of landscapes, residences, street scenes, and boating scenes.
  - New Brunswick, Canada, Series 1 Subseries 1
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    This subseries contains glass plate negatives of locations in New Brunswick, Canada. Specific locations include Beaver Harbor, Blacks Harbor, Lake Nasahie, Oak Bay, Pennfield, St. Andrews, St. George, and some unidentified locations. The material in this subseries is dated from 1893-1902, though much of the material remains undated. As a whole, this subseries focuses on topographical images of landscapes, boating scenes, and the Prescott family home.
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 1)
      General
      Village scene.
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 2)
      Image of a Lighthouse.
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 3)
      Indian Tent (No. 1).
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 4)
      Surf on the rocks, 1st prize.
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 5)
      Surf on the rocks.
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 6)
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 7)
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 8)
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 9)
      Lawrie on the Beach.
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 10)
      Beach at Beaver Harbor.
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 11)
      Boats at Beaver Harbor.
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 12)
      Boats.
    - Beaver Harbor, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 13)
    - Blacks Harbor, New Brunswick, 1902 August; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 14)
      Weirs at Blacks Harbor
    - Blacks Harbor, New Brunswick, 1902 August; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 15)
    - Lake Nasahie, New Brunswick, 1902 August 21; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 16)
      Prescott and Seward in canoe on Outlet of Lake Nasahie; Trip to New Brunswick
    - Lake Nasahie, New Brunswick, 1902 August 21; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 17)
      Prescott and Seward floating canoe over Outlet of Lake Nasahie; Trip to New Brunswick
    - Oak Bay, New Brunswick, 1901 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 18)
      Pines at Youngs Point, Oak Bay, N.B.
    - Oak Bay, New Brunswick, 1902 September 6; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 19)
      Pigs in field on Oak Bay Road, N.B.
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 20)
      Children and lamb.
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 21)
      Home--Girls in dooryard.
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 22)
      Pennfield Toboggan Team (sign)
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 1)
      Prescott Home; landscape
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 2)
      Prescott Home; landscape with man and woman
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 3)
      Prescott Home; home exterior
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 4)
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 5)
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 6)
      Prescott Home; interior
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 21, Item 7)
      Prescott Home; wharf
    - Pennfield, New Brunswick, 1901 August; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 23)
      Willow Tree at Skeues
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 24)
      Road in front of "Home"; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 25)
      View of "Home" from barn; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 26)
      View of "Home" from Orchard; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 27)
      View of "Home" from Road; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 28)
      View of "Home" from field; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 29)
      View of "Home" with Lawrie and horse; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 1, Item 30)
      Helen feeding the colts; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 1)
      Colts in orchard.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 2)
      Clam roast on beach; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 3)
      Schooner "Mist" on the beach; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 4)
      Geo. Spear's house and geese; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 5)
      Geese at Geo. Spears; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 6)
      Four geese in orchard; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 7)
      Geese; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1894 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 8)
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 9)
      Annie at the Spring; Pennfield, N.B
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 10)
      Coldbrook; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 11)
      School-house; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 12)
      School-house interior; Pennfield, N.B
    - "Pennfield Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 13)
      Hunter's barn and brook; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 14)
      "Hunter's Brook"; Ruins of old mills; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 15)
      "Hunter's Brook"; old dam; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 16)
      Hunter's pond and mill; Pennfield, N.B
    - "Pennfield Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 17)
      Hunter's Pond; Pennfield, N.B.
    - "Pennfield Views", Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 18)
      Boats on shore; Pennfield, N.B.
    - St. Andrews, New Brunswick, 1893 August 25; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 19)
      Lighthouse and wharf; 19-4
    - St. Andrews, New Brunswick, 1893 August 25; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 20)
      Wharf from boat; 19-5
    - St. Andrews, New Brunswick, 1893 August 25; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 21)
      Beach from boat; 19-6
    - St. George, New Brunswick, 1894; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 22)
      Falls of St. George from Lower Bridge.
    - St. George, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 23)
    - St. George, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 24)
    - St. George, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 25)
    - St. George, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 26)
    - St. George, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 27)
      Lower Bridge from edge of dam.
    - St. George, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 28)
      Falls of St. George looking down from dam.
    - St. George, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 29)
      Race-way.
    - St. George, New Brunswick, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 1, Box 2, Item 30)
      Suspension Bridge.
    - St. George, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 1)
      Lighthouse
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 2)
      Boats at Sea
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, 1902 August 14; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 3)
      The "Edith"--off Robinston
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, 1893 August 26; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 4)
      "Our Team" at Dyer's (No. 1); 22-5
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 5)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Building with carriage)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 6)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 7)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Bridge over River)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 8)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Geese in water)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 9)
      Trips to New Brunswick (House under construction)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 10)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Pipe laying on grass)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 11)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Pine trees and stream)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 12)
      Trips to New Brunswick (People in the water)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 13)
      Trips to New Brunswick (River)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 14)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Rocky Stream)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 15)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Rocks and wooden structure)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 16)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Two children with pig)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 17)
      Trips to New Brunwick (Two children with pig)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, 1893 August 26; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 18)
      Trips to New Brunwick (Turkeys on fence)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 19)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Tree leaning over stream)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 20)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Wooden bridge over stream)
    - Unidentified Location, New Brunswick, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 1 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 21)
      Trips to New Brunswick (Water lilies)
  - Illinois, New England, and New York, Series 1 Subseries 2
    This subseries contains glass plate negatives of locations in Illinois, New Enland, and New York. Specific locations include: Fort Sheridan, IL; Holden, MA; Calais, ME; Eastport, ME; Grand Lake, ME; Lubec, ME; St. Croix River, ME; Tomah Stream, ME; and Niagra Falls, NY. The material in this subseries is dated from 1893-1901, though much of the material remains undated. As a whole, this subseries focuses on topographical images of landscapes, boating scenes, and a few campsites.
    - Calais, Maine, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 22)
      Bridge between Calais, ME and St. Stephen, New Brunswick; 19-10
    - Calais, Maine, 1901 September; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 23)
      Dr. F.W. Eaton's House--side view
    - Calais, Maine, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 24)
      Gunning near Calais; "We uns Eaton"; 22-6
    - Calais, Maine, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 25)
      Horse race; time 2.28; 19-11
    - Calais, Maine, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 26)
      Public Library; 19-13
    - Calais, Maine, 1901 October; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 27)
      Skinning the moose
    - Calais, Maine, 1901 October; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 28)
    - Calais, Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 29)
      Wharf; 19-9
    - Dr. Grant's Home, Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 3, Item 30)
      No. 99
    - Eastport, Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 1)
      Wharf; 19-1
    - Fort Sheridan, Illinos, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 2)
      "Estelle Randall".
    - Grand Lake, Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 3)
      Boats
    - Grand Lake, Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 4)
    - Grand Lake, Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 5)
      Camp
    - Grand Lake, Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 6)
      Pyramid Rock
    - Grand Lake, Maine, 1901 October; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 7)
      Sample of Shore
    - Grand Lake, Maine, 1901 October; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 8)
      Whitney Cove; boats at landing
    - Grand Lake, Maine, 1901 October; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 9)
      Whitney Cove; Eaton's camp
    - Holden, Massachusetts, 1900 July; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 10)
      Calves in the lane
    - Holden, Massachusetts, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 11)
      South view from pasture wall
    - Niagra Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 12)
      American falls from Canada; Velox - 2 1/4 min
    - Niagra Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 13)
      American falls with horseshoe; falls in distance; taken from Prospect Point; velox - 3 min
    - Niagra Falls, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 14)
      Taken at Devil's Hole State Park, Niagra Falls; American Shore; Whirlpool rapids; Velox - 4 min
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 15)
      The Captain
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 16)
      The Cook
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 17)
      The Engineer
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 18)
      Evans on the end of bowsprit
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 19)
      Evans or Harry in Crosstrees
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 20)
      Evans and Harry just before leaving ship
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 21)
      Leaving Hampton Rhodes
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 22)
      The mate and kittens
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 23)
      Schooner off Shovel Hull Shoals
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 24)
      The sprague after the storm
    - N.N.L. - Schooner Trip to Boston, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 25)
      The sprague wing to wing
    - Lubec, Maine, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 26)
      The Narrows from boat; 19-2
    - Lubec, Maine, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 27)
      Terry boat and wharf; 19-3
    - St. Croix River, Maine, 1893 August 25; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 28)
      Wreck on shore; 19-7
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, 1894 September 5; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 29)
      Steamer "State of Maine".
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 4, Item 30)
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 1)
      Wake of the S.S. "State of Maine".
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, 1893 August 25; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 2)
      Steamer "New Brunswick".
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, Undated; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 3)
      Steamer "Cumberland".
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, 1894 September 6; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 4)
      Steamer "Rose Standish".
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, 1894 September 29; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 5)
      Schooners in Portland Harbor, ME.
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, 1894 September 29; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 6)
    - "Steamers, etc.," New England, 1893 September; Series 1, Sub Series 2 (Carton 2, Box 5, Item 7)
      Schooner at Glouchester, MA.